MORGAN ATWOOD

4325 Baywood way, Sacramento CA, 95864 714-770-9163 atwood.morganj@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm a Front End Engineer with over 4 years of experience, currently working at the 2nd largest cookware distributor in the U.S. Proficient in TypeScript, React/Redux, C#, Microsoft Azure, and MSSQL. Additionally, I've been expanding my skill set by building microservices with NestJS (TypeScript backend), TypeORM, and RabbitMQ.

I'm based in the San Francisco/Sacramento area and open to new opportunities where I can both apply my current expertise and learn new technologies.

GitHub: https://github.com/morigami8

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Development Environments: Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, Sublime Text , Atom, SQL server management studio

Proficient Languages: Typescript, C#, SQL.

Familiar Languages: PHP

Experience with Frameworks/Libraries: Node.js, Express, NestJS, React, Redux, Bootstrap, Foundation, Material UI, thunk, Jest, Webpack, Expect, Babel, Axios, RabbitMQ.

Markup: HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, grid and flexbox.

Team Communication: Azure Devops, Jira, Flow, Basecamp, Tortoise SVN, GIT.

10% time (learning): Creating projections using TypeScript Front and Backend.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MEYER CORPORATION FRONT END DEVELOPER

02/2019 – PRESENT FAIRFIELD, CA

I develop internal tools that require a React/Redux frontend and with Microsoft Azure Cloud Infrastructure. I work alongside most if not all departments within the company to get project requirements and general user understanding of what needs to be done. Love working with a team, don't mind coding solo but I also really enjoy paired programming as well.

- Implement, maintain, and refactor internal tools using React, and Redux.
- All-around development (Frontend/Backend) as the business needs. The majority of my time is in Frontend development.
- Train Junior developers on React/Redux.

MEYER CORPORATION WEB SYSTEMS ADMIN

09/2015 – 02/2019

FAIRFIELD, CA

- -Helped internal developers create system environments that make their development more efficient.
- -Managed multiple WordPress e-commerce sites and their performance utilizing Google Analytics.
- -Built Static pages using PHP for end-users to consume.
- -Managed NGINX and load balancers

FLAVORUS
SOFTWARE ENGINEER (BACK END)

08/2014 - 09/2015 LOS ANGELES, CA

Developed my skills as a back-end engineer by understanding legacy code and how I can impact the code in an

effective way by adding or updating syntax. I work with a small team of developers with various amounts of skill levels in which we help each other tackle problems in our areas of comfort. My responsibilities include but are not limited to the following:

- Maintaining website operability (bug fixing)
- Aesthetical changes
- Creating queries that dynamically show data as it relates to clients, customers, and admins.
- As of April 2015 began a new version of our IOS app using Swift from C# (Xamarin).
- Learned on the job SQL, VB.NET, Swift and any other technologies required of me.
- Authorization and Authentication according to brand.
- Connected our API to different Gateway API's that linked to Merchant accounts.
- Set up content dynamically for automatic emails to clients, customers, and admins.

EDUCATION

Computer Science, California State University, Fullerton

09/2014